# 好久没有下来吃饭了
It’s been a while since the last time I ate out.
# 今天发现 下面的两家小吃店
Today I found out the 2 restaurants
# 都贴上了出租的标志
Are both for lease now
# 现在很多的店都已经正常营业了
Now lots of stores are operating like normal
# 不过要求就是 进入时
But the requirement is while entering
# 必须要戴口罩 必须要检查测体温
You must wear mask and get body temperature measured
# 我要下车买东西了
I’m going to buy some groceries
# 大家乖乖地在这儿等着我
Please wait here
# 嗨  我回来了
Hi I’m back
# 这次买了鸡腿 买了西兰花
This time I bought chicken drumsticks, some broccoli
# 还买了一些水果
I also bought some fruit
# 现在准备回家了
Now I am ready to go home
# 这个时间点 是我要饿的时候了
This time, is the time for me to get hungry
# 蒸米饭
Steam some white rice
# 鸡腿剔骨
Debone the chicken drumsticks
# 我有一双神奇的剪刀手
I’ve got magical scissor hands
# 我妈说 上次我炸的麻花不好看
My mom said last time my fried dough twists were ugly
# 这次我一定要把鸡腿饭做的好看一点
This time I am going to make the chicken meal look better
# 不蒸馒头 争口气
Redemption time
# 做照烧鸡腿饭 方子我都是现找的
I just learned a recipe of teriyaki chicken meal
# 好在材料都有
Good thing I have most of the ingredients
# 现在我们就是把这些腌料放进碗里
Now we are putting the marinating ingredients into the bowl
# 料酒  姜片 黑胡椒 食用油 盐
Chinese cooking wine, sliced ginger, black pepper, cooking oil, salt
# 好浓重的料酒的味道
Very heavy smell of the cooking wine
# 好了 腌着吧
Okay, let it marinate
# 现在的目标就是把鸡皮煎出油来
Now the goal is to crisp the skin, and to get the fat out
# 本鱼还是第一次做 看样子 还是很成功的
It is my fist time making it. Looks like a successful case
# 压实 压实 压实
Press firm, firm, extra firm
# 满满的米饭
Bowl full of rice
# 压实的米饭 才是我对你的爱
Firmly pressed bowl full of rice, is my love to you
# 好了
Okay
# 历经一个多小时 我们总算
After a bit over an hour, we finally
# 把照烧鸡腿饭做完了
Finished the teriyaki chicken meal
# 还是很不错的吧
It looks not bad
# 看这浓郁的汤汁
Look at this thick sauce
# 真的恨不得马上吃掉它
I really want to gorge it
# 这个鸡腿被我煎的金黄金黄的
The chicken leg is fried to perfectly browned
# 而且鸡皮已经煎的有点焦脆了
And the skin is a bit crispy
# 就是微微的酱油的咸味
Just a little bit salty from the soy sauce
# 带蜂蜜的甜味
With some sweetness from the honey
# 鸡腿比较好咬
Very tender chicken, easy to bite into
# 像我这种牙齿不好的
Especially for me who has weak teeth
# 不 我是颌关节不太好
No, I mean weak jaw joint
# 吃这个鸡腿完全没有任何的压力
No pressure in eating the chicken leg
# 汤汁流到米饭上
The sauce got on rice
# 无敌好吃
It tastes extremely good
# 光这个酱汁 就能够吃完3碗饭
With just the sauce, I can finish 3 bowls of rice
# 为什么我一个北方人 对米饭情有独钟呢
Why do I love rice so much as a Northerner (of China)
# 做照烧鸡腿饭 简单易学
The teriyaki chicken meal is easy to make
# 而且
And
# 吃完 就刷一个碗
You only wash one bowl
# 好久没有出去了
I have not gone out for a while
# 最近在家都捂白了好多
My skin have gotten a lot lighter